Guide to the ILGWU. Sol Chaikin papers,
ILGWU. Sol Chaikin papers,
- Series X. Speeches
  - Statement Concerning U.S. Trade Policy Made Before the Subcommittee on Trade, Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    April 3
  - Sewn Into a Corner. Testimony Concerning Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    article concerning imports, appeared in the New York Times, drafts sent to the times are included, May 22; June 13
  - Testimony Concerning the President's New Tax Proposals [Folder 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    given before the Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of representatives, June 13
  - Testimony Concerning the President's New Tax Proposals [Folder 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    given before the committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, June 13
  - Statement Concerning Imports, Made Before the Subcommittee on Census and Population. Draft Statement Concerning Imports. Actual Statement Concerning Imports Made Before the Subcommittee on International Trade, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    Committee on Post Office and Civil service, U.S. House of Representatives, June 26; before the Subcommittee on International Trade, committee on Finance, U.S. Senate, July 15; Committee on Finance, U.S. Senate, July 15
  - Actual Statement Concerning Imports Made Before the Subcommittee on International Trade, Committee on Finance, U.S. Senate. Labor Leader Calls for National Trade Policy, Letter to the Editor, The New York Times, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    July 15; July 22
  - A Look at Health Care. A Union's Stake in Higher Education, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    printed in the NCCMP Update, November; given at a Columbia University seminar, Higher education and Economic Development: Interaction in a technological Society, November 20
  - A Union's Stake in Higher Education, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    given at a Columbia University Seminar, Higher Education and Economic Development: Interaction in a Technological Society, November 20
  - Labor and the National Social Conscience, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    given at the Brandeis University/Heller School's Program "The National Social Conscience," November 21
  - Labor and the National Social Conscience. Why Americans Should Back Textile Trade Act, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    given at the Brandeis University/Heller School's Program, "The National Social Conscience," November 21; letter to the editor of the Miami Herald, which appeared in the newspaper, December 28
  - Trade and the American Worker (Box 50, Folder 17)
    given for the "Deficit Debate:Critical Crossroads to the Future"
  - Statement Regarding Imports Submitted to the Democratic Policy Commission, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    Summary Attached, January 20
  - Interview Concerning the Imbalance of Trade Which Appeared in "Governance, Harvard Journal of Public Policy," Article and Actual Interview Transcripts, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    Summer-Fall
  - The American Labor Movement in International Trade (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Speech Concerning Challenges that Unions Must Face (Box 50, Folder 21)
    given at the ACTWU Convention
  - The American Apparel and Textile Industry (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Factsheet on Apparel and Textile Imports. Opening Comments, Concerning Inflation (Box 50, Folder 23)
    Made at Local 155's Seminar on Tax Reform and Inflation
- Series XI. Financial records
  Filed alphabetically by subject heading
  - Audit Department. Re Outstanding Audit Bills, Collection, and Other Financial Information [Folder 1 of 2], 1976- 1984 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Audit Department. Re Outstanding Audit Bills, Collection, and Other Financial Information [Folder 2 of 2], 1976- 1984 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Finance. General, 1981-1986 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    General Financial Information; Census Information by Region
  - Financial Reports [Folder 1 of 2], 1971-1983 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Reports of Benefit and general Funds
  - Financial Reports [Folder 2 of 2], 1971-1983 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Reports of benefit and general funds
  - Financial Reports. Los Angeles Joint Board, 1974-1977 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Financial Statements; Audit Reports
  - Financial. Staff Salaries, 1977-1978 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    general information
  - Georgia Apparel Manufacturing Company, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    re Strike Expenses
  - ILGWU. Realty. General, 1984-1985 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - Income Tax Returns. Federal, 1938-1950 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    Completed forms of Local 226. Springfield, Massachusetts
  - Insurance, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    Information and Worksheets for various Proposals for ILGWU Insurance Programs
  - Investments [Folder 1 of 2], 1973-1985 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    Correspondence and Statistical information regarding investment programs and policies
  - Investments [Folder 2 of 2], 1973-1985 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    correspondence and statistical information regarding investment programs and policies
  - Ledger Sheets, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    Alphabetical by organization
  - Percentages of Contributions to the Benefit Funds, 1971-1973 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    statistical information filed alphabetically by company
  - Remuneration to Non-153 Employees Financial Information (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Staff. Payroll, Insurance, Etc.[Folder 1 of 2], 1973-1980 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    Memos, correspondence, statistical information regarding ILGWU staff salaries and insurance
  - Staff. Payroll, Insurance, Etc. [Folder 2 of 2], 1973-1980 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    memos, correspondence, statistical information regarding ILGWU staff salaries and insurance
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1982 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    1 bound volume. Ledger book; oversize bound volume ledger book, archives department on top of box
- Series XII. Publications
  Includes: (1) publications by Sol C. Chaikin, filed alphabetically by title; (2) miscellaneous articles and clippings; and (3) miscellaneous publications. Box 53 contains Mr. Chaikin's calendars.
  - American Apparel and Textile Industry (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Apparel Imports: A Threat to the Nation (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Industrial Policy and the Labor-Intensive Sector (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - A Labor Viewpoint: Another Opinion [Folder 1 of 5] (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - A Labor Viewpoint: Another Opinion [Folder 2 of 5] (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - A Labor Viewpoint: Another Opinion [Folder 3 of 5] (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - A Labor Viewpoint: Another Opinion [Folder 4 of 5] (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - A Labor Viewpoint: Another Opinion [Folder 5 of 5] (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Labor's Critical Issue: The Two-Tiered Society (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Let's Control Imports Better (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - The Needs of the Labor-Intensive Sector (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Subminimum Wage: Sub-Par Idea (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Toward a Rational Development Policy (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Trade, Investment, and Industrialization: Myth and Reality (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Where Do We Go From Here (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 1 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 16)
    see also box 57
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 2 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 3 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 4 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 5 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 6 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings [Folder 7 of 7] (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - Calendars (Box 53, Folder 1)
- XIII. Photographs (Box 54)
  Photographs transferred to Box 54, 5780/083 P. ILGWU. Sol Chaikin Photographs.
- Series XIV. Miscellaneous
  Memorabilia and tape recorded speeches
  - Memorabilia and Miscellaneous (Box 55, Folder 1)
    yearbook, 1934; Convention credential; democratic national convention credentials; memorabilia from South Korean trip; early 1947 New England contracts; Award program booklets; letters and photos re League for Industrial Democracy; Buttons [political and other]; other miscellaneous
  - Tape Recordings (Box 56, Folder 1)
    Tape recordings transferred to Box 56, 5780/083 AV. ILGWU. Sol Chaikin audio-visual materials.
  - Tape recordings (Box 58)
    Tape recordings transferred to Box 58, 5780/083 AV. ILGWU. Sol Chaikin audio-visual materials.
- Series XV. Additional Papers
  Received after Mr. Chaikin's death
  - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 59)